EFRAIN PIZARRO

MULTIMEDIA ENGINEER

Documentation in order for the EU

(+34) 676 68 51 26

✓ efrainps290@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/efrain-pizarro-soto/

Hello! I am passionate about **data, web development and graphic design.** I am currently on an exciting path that combines skills as a **BI developer, data engineer, and data scientist.** I have more than **4 years of experience** helping my clients get the most **value** from their data, allowing them to make faster business decisions with less uncertainty.

I have had the opportunity to participate in really significant projects, especially in the pharmaceutical sector.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Wadua Analytics S.A.S.

(Consultant for technological solutions based on data analytics)

Jr. BI Consultant (July 2019 - July 2020)

BI Consultant (July 2020 – December 2021)

UX Engineer (December 2021 – present)

Functions:

- Work closely with users to understand and clearly define their needs.
- Use various tools such as Python, SQL, and Power BI to effectively extract and clean data.
- Perform in-depth data analysis to discover relevant patterns and trends.
- Develop analytical models that support informed decision making and improve reporting performance.
- Design intuitive and visually appealing dashboards following user experience (UX) best practices.

Achievements:

- I built a culture of visualization at our company by training new team members and colleagues from other areas on best practices for presenting information in an impactful way. As a result, our team now delivers faster, more efficient and engaging presentations, generating greater interest from the audience.
- I increased the **confidence** of our clients by constantly demonstrating the capacity and ability of our company to add value in the visualization and creation of dashboards. By **proposing** new ways to represent data, I've made our clients more responsive and flexible by taking **innovative** approaches to data visualization.

TECHNICAL SKILLS BI development Power BI Tibco Spotfire Looker Pvthon SQL Machine learning Web development HTML CSS Javascript React is FastApi Node js **Graphic design** Adobe Illustrator Adobe Photoshop Adobe After Effects Adobe Premier Adobe XD

Figma

Spanish

English

LANGUAGES

EDUCATION

University Autónoma de Occidente

(Cali, Colombia)

Specialization in Big Data Analytics (2020 - 2021)

Multimedia Engineering (2015 - 2020)

Transformational Leadership School (2019)

NEXT U

(Colombia)

Web Frontend (2022)

IBM SkillsBuild

(Spain)

Power BI Desktop course (2023)

SOFT SKILLS

- Effective communication
- Problem resolution
- Curiosity and continuous learning
- Teamwork
- Analytical thinking
- Time management and organization
- Adaptability
- Creativity
- Inspiration to the team
- Team empowerment
- Change management